Jensen, Vernon H. Additional Research and Office Files /4096
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Vernon H. Jensen Additional Research and Office Files
1946-1978
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Jensen, Vernon H.
/4096
7 cubic feet
7 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Includes research documents, correspondence, notes, mss. and publications.
3107921
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, January 13, 2016
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, September 30, 2016
Biographical / Historical
Vernon Jensen (July 10, 1907 September 27, 1998) was a founding faculty member of Cornell's New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations.
A graduate of Brigham Young University (BS '32), Jensen worked as a substitute teacher in Salt Lake City after college before leaving to pursue graduate study at the University of California at Berkeley (PhD '39). Shortly before completing his degree, Jensen began teaching at the University of Colorado. He taught at UC from 1937 to 1946, during which time he also served as a consultant to the National Defense Mediation Board (1941) and a public panel member, mediator and arbitrator for the National War Labor Board (1942) and Wage Stabilization Director of the NWLB's Ninth Region (1942-1944).
Jensen was among the founding faculty of the School of Industrial and Labor Relations, joining Cornell in 1946. Jensen became Associate Dean of the ILR School in 1965 and was elected to Cornell's Board of Trustees in 1973. In addition to numerous articles, Jensen wrote four books, Lumber and Labor (1945), Heritage of Conflict (1950), Collective Bargaining in the Nonferrous Metal Industry (1955), and Hiring of Dockworkers and Employment Practices in the Ports of New York, London, Liverpool, Rotterdam, and Marseilles (1964).
See the Cornell University Faculty Memorial Statement for Professor Vernon Jensen: http://hdl.handle.net/1813/18668
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /3002: Vernon Jensen Papers /4007: Vernon Jensen Additional Records /4067: Vernon Jensen Longshore Research Files /4128: Vernon Jensen Additional Papers /4137: Vernon Jensen Additional Files
Jensen, Vernon H.; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations --Faculty.
3107921
- Miscellaneous, 1894-1944 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 1886 Mediation Study, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Transportation and General Workers Union; The Law and You (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Scope and Contents
  Bound
- Port of London - Piece-Work Rates, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Ministry of War Transport - Port of Liverpool and Birkenhead, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- The London Short Sea Traders' Association -and- The Transport and General Workers' Union, 1931-1957 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Transport and General Workers' Union Region 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Port of London Authority - Licensed Watermen (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Port of London Piece - Work Rates, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Port of London Piece - Work Rates, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Port of Liverpool Dock Labour Joint Committee, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Transport and General Workers -and- Employers' Association of the Port of Liverpool (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Transport and General Workers' Union -and- Employers' Association of the Port of Liverpool (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Dock Labour Joint Committee, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Dock Labour Joint Committee, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Transport and General Workers' Union, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Transport and General Workers Union Shop Stewards Handbook, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Transport and General Workers Union Members Handbook, 1947-1959 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Transport and General Workers Union (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Transport and General Workers Union Shopstewards Handbook, 1952-1957 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Transport and General Workers' Union Rules, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Transport and General Workers' Union Rules, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Transport and General Workers Union - The Law and You, 1956-1960 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Transport and General Workers Union Shop Stewards Handbook, 1952-1957 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- The Company of Waterman and Lightermen of the River Thames, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Transport and General Workers Union, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Transport and General Workers Union, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Labor History of Colorado, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Dock Labour Joint Committee (Box 1, Folder 29)
- V. H. Jensen, 1947-1957 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Collective Bargaining (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Thomsen in 1959 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- THB NIEUWS, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  Bound,
- THB NIEUWS, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- THB NIEUWS, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- THB NIEUWS, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- THB NIEUWS, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- THB NIEUWS, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- THB NIEUWS, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- THB NIEUWS, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- THB NIEUWS, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- THB NIEUWS, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- THB NIEUWS, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- THB NIEUWS, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Rotterdam en Amerika, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Scheepvaart Vereeniging Zuid, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Scheepvaart Vereeniging Noord Amsterdam, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Jaarverslag, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Jaarverslag, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Jaarverslag, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Jaaverslag, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Jaarverslag, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Jaarverslag, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Wet op de Ondermings-Raden (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Memorandums, 1946-1957 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Collective Bg. Nonferrous U of Calif. Monographs, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Correspondence Dealing with, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Some Reflections on Beginnings (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Research-- History of Med. And Arb. - NYS, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Labor Relations Law (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Vernon Jensen, 1942-1947 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Trip to Geneva, Switzerland and London, England, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Heritage of Conflict (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Dispute Settlement Bibliography, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Heritage of Conflict - Misc. Correspondence, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Agreement - The Enclosed Docks Employers, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Report of the Committee of Inquiry into the Major Ports of Great Britain, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- The Enclosed Docks Employers, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- The enclosed Docks Employers - The Transport and General Workers' Union, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Copy: Transport + General Workers Union, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Official Inquiries, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- National Dock Labour Board, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- G.B. (Great Britain), 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Rotterdam, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Rotterdam, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Marseille, 1950-1955 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Belgium - General, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- I.L.A., 1963 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Articles from Deseret News giving Background of Situation in Butte, Montana Re: Strikes, Union Set-Up, etc., 1955 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Confidential For Commission Members Only Draft Report of the Railroad Marine Workers Commission, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- NYSA-ILA Arbitration Seniority, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Puerto Rico, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Spanish
- New York Harbor Railroad Commission, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Aide - Memoire, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Les Enterprises De Manutention, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Port Autonome de Marseille, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Jaarverslag, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Keezer "Research note on high test techniques for Mediating labor Disputes.", 1955 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Booklets, 1951-1952 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- NYSA-ILA, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Wages and Conditions Schedule, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Tabellen, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- ILA vs. New York Shipping Association, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- ILA vs. New York Shipping Association, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- ILA vs. New York Shipping Association, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- ILA vs. New York Shipping Association, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- ILA vs. New York Shipping Association, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- ILA vs. New York Shipping Association, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- ILA vs. New York Shipping Association, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- ILA vs. New York Shipping Association, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- ILA vs. New York Shipping Association, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- ILA vs. New York Shipping Association, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- University of Leeds, England, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- B, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- C, 1958-1965 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- D, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- E, 1951-1956 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- F, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Fund for the Advancement of Education, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- G, 1958-1961 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Gulick, Charles A., 1962 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- H, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- I, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- J, 1956-1962 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- K, 1956-1963 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- L, 1959-1964 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- M, 1963-1965 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- N, 1958-1964 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- O, 1954-1963 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- P, 1956-1965 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- R, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- S, 1963-1965 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- T, 1946-1965 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- U-V, 1964-1965 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- U-V, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- W, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- XYZ, 1957-1961 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- XYZ, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Research and Education Committees N.A.A., 1965 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- National Academy - Arbitrators, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Addressing Technology, Growth and Change: Papers Designed to Stimulate Awareness and to Encourage, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Addressing Technology, Growth and Change: Papers Designed to Stimulate Awareness and to Encourage, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Addressing Technology, Growth and Change: Papers Designed to Stimulate Awareness and to Encourage, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Addressing Technology, Growth and Change: Papers Designed to Stimulate Awareness and to Encourage, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 17)